Jamey David Lazarus

Web Applications Architect

SF Bay Area, CA (913) 956-9893 jmslazarus@gmail.com https://jmslazarus.github.io

Summary

Proficient and creative UI Engineer with over 15 years of web application development experience.

Areas of Focus: Leading a team of engineers, developing intuitive and accessible applications

Technologies: JavaScript, ES6+, Typescript, SASS/SCSS, Webpack, Rollup, Node, Express, React,

Angular, WebGL, Three.js, ChartsJS, D3, WebSockets, ServiceWorker, WebRTC, SQL, MySQL, GraphQL, Storybook, Git/GitHub/CoPilot, CI/CD, Jenkins, Ansible, Piper, Jest,

Cypress, Mobile, Cross Browser, Responsive Design, WCAG, Accessibility

Skills:

- ✓ Leading and nurturing a team of developers utilizing remote collaboration tools
- ✓ Optimization techniques for fetching, manipulating and rendering big data
- ✓ Configuring development environments and CI/CD pipeline
- ✓ Writing thorough documentation, best practices, and clean self-documenting code
- ✓ Creating seamless user experiences across sessions and devices
- ✓ Responsive design techniques for mobile and desktop
- ✓ Leveraging E2E and unit testing to maintain a high percentage of code coverage

Experience

Visa Lead Data Engineer 10/2022 – 11/2024

- Architect for Visa's Federated Data Management UI and oversaw 8 major releases
- Technologies utilized included React, Typescript, Material-UI, Java, MySQL
- Technical lead and manager for a team of five developers in multiple time zones
- Handled CI/CD creation and management via CloudView, Jenkins, Piper, Ansible and Docker
- Ensured strict adherence to WCAG and VGAR accessibility standards and certifications
- Maintained >75% code coverage with Jest-based unit tests, plus Functional and E2E testing
- UI/UX user research, creation of mockups and final design for dozens of new feature stories

4/2021 - 10/2022

- UI Team Lead for Visa's Parsec Data Platform
- Technologies utilized included React, Angular, Node.JS, GraphQL
- Maintained development of 4 major UI applications, 5 dashboards, and a dozen+ smaller tools

Dun & Bradstreet Principal UI Engineer 6/2019 – 1/2021

Oversaw the design and development of 7 different JS, Node, React, and Angular projects

- Worked closely with Product Management/Design Team at all stages of the product lifecycle
- Utilized NodeJS/Express for serving the frontend, proxies, and establishing API endpoints
- Migrated AngularJS legacy apps to newer frameworks like Angular 2+/Typescript and ReactJS

Lattice Engines Principal UI Engineer 5/2015 – 6/2019

Lattice Engines was purchased by Dun and Bradstreet in 2019

TheFind Senior UI Engineer 6/2007 – 3/2015

- Maintained and contributed to custom libraries.
- Responsible for new feature development and supporting tools for our custom JS framework.
- Project lead on several Web applications and mobile projects in the online consumer sales space.
- TheFind was purchased by Facebook in 2015

Personal Projects

Elation WebGL Engine and JavaScript Framework

- A senior contributor to the project and member of the core development team.
- Developed many key components including ways of handling inheritance, namespacing, custom events, and various custom UI controls and utility functions.

Elation Window Manager

- Designed and implemented a robust window management system to host custom mini-apps
- Window frames could be resized from any corner/edge, rolled up or moved via their title bar
- Grouping could treat multiple windows from the same mini-app together for certain behaviors
- A system to track z-indexing was implemented to handle focus management
- Presets for various window types and interactive components (buttons, dropdowns, etc)

Stella Imperia

An Elite-Style WebGL multiplayer space FPS game

- Created all gameplay code, 3D models, textures, and sounds
- Generated a galaxy of unique star systems to explore based on procedural design techniques
- Created a 3D cockpit with HUD, mapped screens and a holographic radar
- Developed numerous ship systems, weapons, and various particle effects
- Coded menus and configuration screens using the Elation Window Manager

Education

Keiser College Fort Lauderdale, FL Computer Programming

Languages: C, C++, JAVA, JavaScript, HTML Systems: Windows, MacOS, Linux, UNIX

Lynn University Boca Raton, FL Graphic Design

Applications: Maya, 3D Studio Max, Blender, Photoshop